Curriculum Vitae Avital Sternin

Luucation	
2014.09 – present	 The University of Western Ontario M.Sc. Candidate in Psychology – Behavioural and Cognitive Neuroscience Supervisors: Dr. Jessica A. Grahn and Dr. Adrian M. Owen Project: Classifying music perception and imagination using EEG
2009.09 – 2014.04	 B.Sc. Neuroscience (Honours) – Supervisor: Dr. Sidney Segalowitz Project: Electrophysiological evidence of altered visual processing in adults suffering from blocked pattern vision during infancy (4th year honour's thesis) Dean's Honors list 2010-2014
Awards	
2015.09-2016.08	 Canada Graduate Scholarships – Master's Program - \$17500 Awarded by the National Science and Engineering Research Council Awarded to work with Dr. Jessica Grahn and Dr. Adrian Owen at the University of Western Ontario.
2015.09-2016.08	Ontario Graduate Scholarship - \$15000 • Declined
2013.05-2013.08	 Undergraduate Student Research Award - \$6000 Awarded by the National Science and Engineering Research Council Awarded to work with Dr. Sid Segalowitz in Brock University's Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience Lab.
Publications	
2015.10	Stober, S., Sternin, A. , Owen, A.M., Grahn, J.A. (2015). Towards Music Imagery Information Retrieval: Introducing the OpenMIIR Dataset of EEG Recordings from Music Perception and Imagination. <i>Proceedings of the 16th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR '16). Malaga, Spain.</i>
2015.08	Segalowitz, S. J., Sternin, A. , Lewis, T. L., Dywan, J., & Maurer, D. Electrophysiological Evidence of Altered Visual Processing in Adults who Experienced Visual Deprivation During Infancy <i>Submitted to Neuropsychologia: NSY-D-15-00682</i> .
2015.06	Sternin, A. , Stober, S., Owen, A.M., Grahn, J.A. Tempo Estimation from the EEG signal during perception and imagination of music. <i>Proceedings of the</i> 1 st <i>International Workshop on Brain-Computer Music Interfacing. Plymouth, UK.</i>

Conference Presentations – oral

Education

2015.09 Fifth Annual Cognitive Based Music Informatics Research (Toronto, ON)

- Stober, S.*, **Sternin, A.,** Owen, A.M., Grahn, J.A.
- Similarity and feature learning for EEG recordings of music perception and imagination
- Awarded the Best Paper Award

2015.06 First International Workshop on Brain-Computer Music Interfacing (Plymouth, UK)

- Sternin, A.*, Stober, S., Owen, A.M., Grahn, J.A.
- Tempo Estimation from the EEG signal during perception and imagination of music

Relevant Experience

2016.03	Inspiring Young Women in STEM Conference – Western Women in Neuroscience • Executive committee member
	 Liaised with local industry partners and organized the conference Industry Expo
2016.02	 Lead Organizer of an Undergraduate Outreach Symposium at Western University Organized Graduate students to give mentorship talks during Bring an Undergrad to Grad School Day 2016
2014-2016	Western Undergraduate Psychology Journal – Graduate Student Editorial Board Member Review articles before publication in the journal
2015.07	Program Support Team – Society for Music Perception and Cognition 2015 • Responsible for grouping submitted abstracts based on topic into conference sessions.

Teaching Experience

2014.09 – present Graduate Teaching Assistant at the University of Western Ontario

- Psychology Research Methods (2nd year)
- Nominated for a Graduate Student Teaching Award (2015)